# Janet Melatti, OTR/L

 $770\text{-}883\text{-}4816 \mid 111\ 108^{th}\ Avenue\ NE,\ A513,\ Bellevue,\ 98004 \mid https://janetychen.github.io \mid Jay.Melatti@outlook.com$ 

Self-taught software developer and board-certified occupational therapist. Clinical experience in leading and mentoring incoming professionals through education and collaboration with appropriate medical professions to deliver optimal prescribed treatment plan and discharge prognosis. Project management experience in Agile Development for web development. Committed to adopting innovative technology practices in software development in healthcare application and other fields. Pursing a lifelong passion of contributing to the innovative advancements in software development.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Georgia State University, Atlanta, GA

August 2019

Master in Occupational Therapy, Byrdine E. Lewis College of Nursing and Health Professions

### The University of Georgia, Athens, GA

May 2017

Bachelor of Science in Health Promotion, College of Public Health

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Fox Rehabilitation - Home Health: Occupational Therapist/Clinical Instructor – New York, NY Dec 2019-Aug 2021

- Clinician instructor and mentor to train new graduate therapists from onboarding to full-case load on Raintree use.
- Lead, prescribe, and create client-centered treatment plans. Modify scope per progression and fluctuation from draft admission, evaluation, to discharge completion.
- Collaborate with medical personal creating an interpersonal treatment team between physician, physical therapist, speech therapist, caregivers, and family members.
- Educate patients and family members on prescribed assistive technology and durable medical equipment.
- Modify assistive technology and durable medical equipment based on client goals.
- Top 10% on clinical team in documentation score, scheduling efficiency, and high number of private pay return clients.

#### Fox Rehabilitation - Home Health: Internship Fieldwork Level II - New York, NY

Feb 2019-May 2019

- Provided and documented assessments, treatments, and discharge planning for a full caseload of patients on Raintree
- Educated patients and caregivers on adaptive equipment, safety awareness, and home modifications

#### **Jersey City Medical Center - Acute Care:** Internship Fieldwork Level II – Jersey City, NJ May 201

May 2019-Aug 2019

- Provided and documented assessments, treatments, and discharge planning for a full caseload of patients on Cerner
- Educated patients and caregivers on adaptive equipment, safety awareness, and home modifications
- Interdisciplinary practices with physicians, surgeons, nursing staff, therapy technicians, collaborative therapist efforts

#### Community Friendship Inc. - Mental Health: Intern Fieldwork Level I – Atlanta, GA

June 2018

- Assisted with occupational therapy assessments for homeless patients with mental illness
- Communicated with physicians on client care and educated clients on the use of the medical research on the internet, environmental safety, sleep health, and nutrition

## **Big Stride Therapy - Pediatric Hippotherapy:** Intern Fieldwork Level I – Alpharetta, GA 2018

Jan 2018-May

- Assisted with therapy sessions for children with Down syndrome, Cerebral Palsy, and Spina bifida
- Assisted in education of client and caregivers on horse safety, posture, and the use of hippotherapy as an occupational therapy treatment modality

#### Winship Cancer Institute of Emory Healthcare Hospital: Intern – Atlanta, GA

Jan 2017-May2017

- Created continuing education program using a flipped classroom approach for future volunteers and employees
- Referred patients and their families to external mental and physical health resources
- Managed 200+ volunteers and raised over \$200,000 in a single event for the cancer research team.
- Project Managed Agile Methodology work stream launching Winship webpages and contributor.

https://winshipcancer.emory.edu/support-winship/volunteer/arts-in-health

#### HONORS/AWARDS

State of Georgia Zell-Miller Scholarship Recipient	2012-2017
Athens Game Jam Hackathon First Place Recipient: Best Game Winner	April 3, 2016
CDC Principles of Prevention Certification	Fall 2015
UGA Academic Honesty Creative Contest First Place Winner: Original Video	May 2014